porteliotfestival.com 2019-04-01

# Privacy Policy - Port Eliot Festival

The website www.porteliotfestival.com is owned and operated by Port Eliot Festival Ltd, Registered Company number 07100762.

### INTRODUCTION

Protecting your privacy as a user of the Website is important to us and we strive to keep all information relating to you confidential in accordance with this statement. As part of the normal operation of our services you may voluntarily provide us with information about yourself (“Personal Data”). The purpose of this Privacy Statement is to explain what Personal Data we collect about you, how that Personal Data might be used and how we protect your Personal Data and privacy.

We will be happy to answer any enquiries from you regarding this Privacy Statement, the Personal Data we hold about you or the use we make of it. If you have any queries or comments, or wish to correct, update, amend or remove any information we hold about you, please contact us at info@porteliotfestival.com

It should be noted that this policy applies to this website only, and there is an additional Policy which applies to [The TicketSellers (TTS)](http://www.theticketsellers.co.uk/) website, the registered online ticket agency for Port Eliot Festival.

### WHAT DATA DO WE COLLECT AND HOW?

If you are merely visiting the public areas of the Website, we do not collect any Personal Data about you. However, we may automatically collect information about your visits, such as browsing patterns. Information collected in this way does not reveal your contact details or any type of Personal Data. This information is only used in aggregate form to analyse, manage and develop the Website and is not linked to any individual.

If you are a member of the website forum or on our newsletter mailing list, we will collect and hold certain Personal Data about you when you register. The Personal Data collected by us will include your name and e-mail address only. From time to time you may also provide other Personal Data which we need to provide you with the service you request, such as your credit card details, other information about yourself, your preferences or your experiences.

If you post comments or reviews on the Website, it is entirely up to you what Personal Data you disclose. In doing so, you freely give us consent to hold that data and to publish it on the Website. We may also ask your consent to publish your comments in other marketing materials and press releases that we publish.

### HOW DO WE USE MEMBERS’ PERSONAL DATA?

We will use all Personal Data for the purpose of providing you with the services you have requested in accordance with the Conditions. We take steps to limit the Personal Data we use in this way to what is necessary for the contract between us.

If you have given us consent to do so, we may use your Personal Data to let you know about other services, initiatives, products, and news about Port Eliot Festival.

We also use Personal Data in aggregate form to monitor and improve our services, including continuing development of this website. These uses of data are in our legitimate interests to continue to provide the community with excellent events and related services. We will always ensure that your interests, rights and freedoms are resected in the use of your Personal Data.

The Website may make available chat rooms, forums, message boards, and news groups. Please remember that any Personal Data that you disclose in these areas of the Website becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose any information on them.

### HOW DO WE PROTECT MEMBERS’ PERSONAL DATA?

When you input any Personal Data into the Website or request services from us, we use appropriate physical, electronic and managerial security measures to try to prevent that Personal Data from being accessed by unauthorised persons and to ensure that you may input Personal Data safely. This means that sometimes we may ask for proof of identity before we disclose Personal Data to you.

### THIRD PARTIES

Third parties are employed to manage the website, develop the site or manage your data on our behalf. They will be required to adhere to this privacy statement. If you have given us your details to be a volunteer or get involved, it may be the case a trusted group will be given your email contact for the purpose for which you have given us your details only. We will not give your details to any other third party for any reason other than is stated here.

We reserve the right to access and disclose Personal Data to comply with applicable laws and lawful government requests or requests by the police investigating suspected illegal activities, to operate our systems properly or to protect ourselves or other the Website users. We also reserve the right to disclose Personal Data to third parties if a complaint arises concerning your use of the Website, and that use is deemed by us to be inconsistent with the Conditions.

### INTERNATIONAL TRANSFER

Some Personal Data may be stored and processed outside of the EEA. Where information is transferred outside of the EEA, we ensure that appropriate safeguards are in place to protect your information to the same or an equivalent level as would be found in UK and EU data protection legislation. The safeguards we use are:

  * Ensuring the country is the subject of an EU adequacy decision; or
  * Ensuring the company is a member of an adequate. Legally-binding scheme such as EU-US Privacy Shield; or
  * Ensuring the contract includes ICO-approved model contract clauses; or
  * Ensuring the organisation is subject to ICO-approved binding corporate rules or an ICO-approved code of conduct.

### RETENTION

In accord with relevant data protection legislation, we will not retain your information for longer than is necessary for the purposes listed above and to deal with any complaint or dispute you may have. If you require further information about our information retention policies, please contact us.

### YOUR RIGHTS

Under UK and EU data protection legislation, you have a number of rights with respect to your information. These include:

  * The right to be informed about the information we hold about you
  * The right of access to the information we hold about you
  * The right to have any errors rectified
  * The right to withdraw consent (where consent is the basis of processing)
  * The right to object to processing

If you have any questions about the information we hold, how we use it or how to exercise these rights, please contact us using the contact details above or contact your account manager if you have one. You can also use the opt-out facilities provided in our marketing emails and in the settings on our website to change your preferences and consents at any time.

### COMPLAINTS

If you have any cause for complaint about the way we care for your information, please do contact us and we will do our best to resolve the situation for you. You also have the right to complain directly to the Information Commisioner’s Office. You can find details of how to contact them here: <https://ico.org.uk/concerns/> or by calling their helpline on 0303 123 1113.

### COOKIES

To make this site work properly, we sometimes place small data files called cookies on your device. The majority of websites do this.

A cookie is a small text file that a website saves on your computer or mobile device when you visit the site. It enables the website to remember your actions and preferences (such as login, language, font size and other display preferences) over a period of time, so you don’t have to keep re-entering them whenever you come back to the site or browse from one page to another.

**How do we use cookies?**

The Website makes use of cookies to enable us to track certain information relating to your use of the Website. We may allow third party advertisers to advertise on the Website and such advertisers may also use cookies to record information about your use of the advertisement which you have seen and the types of things you appear interested in. A number of our pages use cookies to remember:

  * Your display preferences, such as contrast colour settings or font size
  * If you have already replied to a survey pop-up (so you won’t be asked again)
  * If you have agreed (or not) to our use of cookies on this site

Also, some videos embedded in our pages use a cookie to anonymously gather statistics on how you got there and what videos you visited.

Cookies are also stored by Google Analytics, the Google service which measures the effectiveness and efficiency of the website.

Enabling these cookies is not strictly necessary for the website to work but it will provide you with a better browsing experience. You can delete or block these cookies, but if you do, some features of this site may not work as intended.

The cookie-related information is not used to identify you personally and the pattern data is fully under our control. These cookies are not used for any purpose other than those described here.

**How to control cookies**

You can control and/or delete cookies as you wish – for details, see aboutcookies.org. You can delete all cookies that are already on your computer and you can set most browsers to prevent them from being placed. If you do this, however, you may have to manually adjust some preferences every time

### SALE, MERGER OR BANKRUPTCY

If the Website is sold to or merges with, or if our business is sold to, merges with or enters a joint venture with another company, you should expect that some or all of the Personal Data collected from the Website may be transferred to the buyer/surviving company. In this incredibly unlikely event, we will either (a) obligate the other company to use any Personal Data transferred by the Website in a manner consistent with this statement, or (b) retain the data. In the event of bankruptcy, we will either (a) destroy the data, or (b) request permission that the data be passed to a third party.

### CHANGES TO THIS STATEMENT

This Privacy Statement is subject to change at any time. We encourage you to review the Privacy Statement regularly for any changes. We will use Personal Data in accordance with the Privacy Statement under which that Personal Data was collected.

This Privacy Statement is part of the Website Terms and Conditions (the “Conditions”) and all defined terms shall have the same meaning as those in the Conditions.

We welcome your questions and comments about privacy issues and the design of the Website. Should you have any comments or a complaint about how we are using your Personal Data, please drop us a line at info@porteliotfestival.com
